<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security-system on Mya Pitzeruse</title>
    <link>https://mjpitz.com/tags/security-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security-system on Mya Pitzeruse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mjpitz.com/tags/security-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extending my Security System with a Raspberry Pi Network Bridge</title>
      <link>https://mjpitz.com/blog/2021/06/16/rpi-network-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjpitz.com/blog/2021/06/16/rpi-network-bridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen a lot, but every so often I come across a device that isn&amp;rsquo;t wi-fi supported.
This latest case was my security system.
On one hand, I like that my cameras aren&amp;rsquo;t taking up bandwidth on my home network and that the system is largely a closed loop.
On the other hand, not having access to my security system without having it tethered into the router is a bit of a pain.
For one, my home networking setup isn&amp;rsquo;t that elegant (yet).
Second, the last thing I want to do is have more stuff out in the open, co-located with my router.
So I decided to get a little creative.
Sure, I could&amp;rsquo;ve bought a wi-fi adapter, but where&amp;rsquo;s the fun in that.
On top of that, I had some other reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if an adapter would work for this system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I eventually want to do some real-time processing of video feed data and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stream that over the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I already have more than a dozen pis around (I wound up using a 3b+ for this).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I describe how I set up and configured a Raspberry Pi to act as a WAN client for connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
