<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>homestead on Mya Pitzeruse</title>
    <link>https://mjpitz.com/tags/homestead/</link>
    <description>Recent content in homestead on Mya Pitzeruse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mjpitz.com/tags/homestead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extending my Security System with a Raspberry Pi Network Bridge</title>
      <link>https://mjpitz.com/blog/2021/06/16/rpi-network-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjpitz.com/blog/2021/06/16/rpi-network-bridge/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen a lot, but every so often I come across a device that isn&amp;rsquo;t wi-fi supported.
This latest case was my security system.
On one hand, I like that my cameras aren&amp;rsquo;t taking up bandwidth on my home network and that the system is largely a closed loop.
On the other, not having access to my security system without having it tethered into the router is a bit of a pain.
For one, my home networking setup isn&amp;rsquo;t that elegant (yet).
Second, the last thing I want to do is have more stuff out in the open, co-located with my router.
So I decided to get a little creative.
Sure, I could&amp;rsquo;ve bought a wi-fi adapter, but where&amp;rsquo;s the fun in that.
On top of that, I had some other reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend money on an adapter for this system.
Even though they aren&amp;rsquo;t that expensive, I would likely need to wait for one to come in which would probably happen &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; I left for my trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually, I want to do some real-time video processing and having a device closer to the box is promising.
This would let me process data straight from the box rather than needing to transmit all that information over wi-fi to another machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, I already have more than a dozen pis around.
For the first version of this, I wound up using a 3b+.
I would likely upgrade this later on when I add the real-time processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I show how I set up and configured a Raspberry Pi to act as a WAN client for a connected device.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>